This is Trigun.
guitar solo
Hello there, little friends.
My name is Vash the Stampede.
I have been a hunter of peace, chasing
the elusive mayfly known as love?
for many, many moons now.
There is no rest for me
in my search of peace.
I meditate diligently every morning.
The subjects are life and love.
I quit after three seconds.
In my search for peace,
I also train diligently.
Thanks, friend, and farewell.
I've also made it my mission
to teach the precious value
of peace to the children who
will one day own the world.
That's cute. Mr.
Vash is being put in strangleholds
by the children again.
That's nice.
I will say it again.
My name is Vash the Stampede.
I am a hunter of peace chasing
the mayfly known as love.
Are you all right, mister?
Eileen?
I'm sorry.
It's just that you look so much
like my poor dead girlfriend.
Please, tell me your name.
I'm Michelle.
Lovely name.
My name is Vash.
Vash the Stampede.
That sounds like...
The name of the outlaw was 60
billion double dollars on his head.
I get that a lot
So anyway, what would you
say to having lunch with me?
Not a chance
You know that we did all this for you.
Yeah, you could try harder
But captain the strategy
doesn't seem to be working.
Can't we try something else?
Hey, it's Neil
Hey, Neil, want to join in?
He's been a real quiet loner lately.
We invite him, but he never comes.
Hmm?
Mr. Vash,
just how long do you think you can perpetuate
this self-indulgent lifestyle of doing
nothing but playing
with children and eating
and sleeping without
doing any work whatsoever?
Eww, a lecture!
You gotta be pretty lame
to take that kind of abuse.
Thank you very much!
Huh?
Come on. Wait, Dad!
Neil! Huh? Hi. Oh, great.
It's just Vash.
Now that wasn't a very warm hello.
Are you helping out?
That's really good, Neil.
That's none of your business.
Hey, now don't be like that.
Wait, does your family run a restaurant?
I'm starved.
Think you can get me something to eat?
You're not getting any
handouts. I know that.
And my mom's off-limits.
What do you mean?
Hey, Mom! Customer!
Hello and welcome! Hey!
Come on in!
Don't wreck the place, stupid!
And what are you doing here,
preacher man? Can't you tell?
I'm lending a helping hand.
Mm-hmm.
It's only natural to
help out those in need.
Here you go. All done.
Thank you, but I feel like
I'm taking advantage of you.
Think nothing of it.
I'm doing it because I want to help.
Now, come on.
Get it while it's warm.
All right.
Here you are. Enjoy.
Did something bad happen?
Thank heaven you asked.
It's a long story, although
it's kind of a short one.
Anyway, this is how it happened.
By chance, I had just stopped
by here to get something to eat.
What are you doing to my mom?
I'm begging you, please.
Just wait a bit longer and I'll
pay you the money I owe you.
I promise.
Lady, you're way past your deadline.
unless you pay off your
debt in full we can't make
any money either and I don't
like that so after that
I decided to use a little
of his gospel to talk them
out of it I asked the lady
what happened she said
that her husband disappeared
leaving his debt behind
but she decided to keep
this place running even the
child is desperate to help
his mother in need it shot
me through the heart could
Could you just sit there?
Could you just ignore that?
That's just awful. Yes? Just awful.
Awful?
Oh, yes. Most definitely. Yes, definitely.
It's the most terrible thing.
You've saved me time.
I was going to go look for
you once we closed shop.
For me? Yep.
The third annual quick draw tournament.
Grand prize, $50,000.
What's this?
To help out a poor family, you're
going to compete. I will? That's right.
All you have to do is show
up there on time tomorrow.
I'll take care of the registration
and paperwork for you.
Why me all of a sudden?
We're helping these good people out here.
Or would you prefer if I turned you in and
get the $60 billion
double dollars instead?
That's not very funny, pal.
Just look at her.
Isn't that a sad face? Yeah.
Not to mention beautiful. Yeah.
For love.
For love and for peace.
A quick draw tournament?
Mm-hmm.
What is going on inside
that pea-brained spiky head?
Any normal person would be able to see the
danger of participating
in such a stupid contest.
I didn't even enter the contest myself.
I was kind of talked into it.
By whom?
The priest we met on the bus.
Hey, Mr.
Vash, if you win the contest,
will you treat me to something?
I'll think about it.
Oh, not again!
I'm having unhappy visions here!
I see this scene in my head
of dozens of hot-shot gunmen
after the $60 billion double
dollars having a macho shootout war!
I'm just taking part in a
fun contest, that's all.
It'll be okay.
You haven't got a single clue, have you?
And you always say the strangest things.
Funny!
The chief says the same thing.
It'll be okay, okay?
It'll be okay.
I guess it will.
Sir, I just thought I should let you know.
When we were going through today's
entries, this name came up.
Vash the Stampede?
This is a most troubling turn of events.
Shall I have this entry withdrawn?
I highly doubt that the
legendary gunman would come
out of hiding for a mere
$50,000 double dollar prize.
It's just a wannabe punk
using the name for kicks.
But, sir...
We'll just let him try it.
Then we'll know if he's the real thing.
We will hold the tournament as planned.
That is all. Go.
Very good, sir.
So what do you think will this do?
Who is it?
It's me. Door's open.
Hey, you still awake?
Lady gave us a present.
Care for a swig?
Ah, sorry about all this.
I didn't really mean to force you into it.
Come on, you planned it from the start.
Well, yeah, but I apologized.
The church?
Huh?
You said earlier that
you came from a church.
Where is this place?
It's 300 aisles from the city of December.
You bring orphans that
far out into the boonies?
It's the only place I've got.
Kids I've met on the way,
with nowhere else to go,
either their parents are
dead or they abandon them.
But, you know, there's kids like Neil.
I really don't want to take him.
There you go, smiling again.
It looks good on you.
Hey, girls!
You don't have to listen through the door.
Come on in!
Well, hello.
I apologize for eavesdropping,
but at least now I understand a
little better, Mr. Vash. Uh, what?
Since it appears that you were
forced this time, I wish you guh...
She means good luck, Mr. Vash.
Give him heck, all right?
Thanks, guys.
Who's drinking? I am! Oh, yeah!
Hey, don't let her have
too much, all right?
Hey, lighten up!
Ah, I feel so hot!
Wow!
Hey, don't do that here!
You go, big girl!
Get your clothes back
on right now! Stop it!
It's time for me!
Oh, we got in some
amazing gunmen this year.
Get a load of that gun.
This is gonna be great.
Mr. Vass and Mr.
Wolfwood haven't arrived yet.
Well, you saw how they were last night.
They'll take their own sweet time.
Besides, it's probably better if they
don't draw too much attention anyway.
So, shall we go?
Please keep your voice down, will ya?
My head really hurts.
You're really a wuss, Vash.
Can't you handle a few drinks?
That wasn't a few drinks.
That was more like a few dallins.
Whatever you say.
Hey, Vash! Hey there!
Is it really true?
Are you gonna help my mom?
Neil, stop.
I can't ask you to do this.
I don't even know who you are.
Hey, we're all friends now.
And besides, I'm not too bad at
this sort of thing, actually.
Oh, what was that?
I didn't even see that.
Bash.
Bash is in the tournament. He is?
You think he can handle it?
There he is, over there.
Looks like a lost cause to me.
Is that the man you spoke of?
He's not bad.
Oops.
Oh no, I hit them all.
You're Vash the Stampede, all right.
I'm standing out too much.
Nah, it'll make the going
that much easier, Vash.
Keep knocking them dead out there.
That goes for you too. Huh? Me too.
If the third-round
contestant, Mr. Nicholas D.
Wolfwood, is present and ready to compete,
step forward now or be disqualified.
What the hell did you sign me up for?
Well, if we both compete,
it'll improve our chances.
What?
Good luck out there, Mr.
Priest Man!
Oh, great.
Hm?
For love and peace.
Wow!
That was so amazing!
How come you're good?
Unfortunately, we have to
live in a dangerous world.
It's for self-protection.
Maybe you're an ex-gunman. Yeah, right.
That's enough.
What is it? Nothing.
You guys are pretty good.
I'm impressed.
But I'm afraid this is
the end of your spree.
This time you ain't
shooting no liquor bottles.
This time is live, one-on-one combat.
You mean you didn't know?!
Can I drop out now?
You dragged me into this with
you and now it's too damn late!
You're very lucky, mister.
It's only your shoulder.
You're good at changing trajectories.
You don't like seeing
people kill each other, huh?
Remember, you're the one
who dragged me into this.
No need to thank me.
We will now commence the
first quarterfinal match.
It's you and me, spineless coward.
Please go easy on me.
I'm really scared.
Ready, go!
Not bad.
Nice...shot.
He was facing backwards
the whole time. Snake.
This is unusual.
So far we haven't had a single
fatality in this year's contest. Hell.
He's actually the real thing.
He's Vash the Stampede.
now you're cool enough
to join our club mr.
wolfwood just told me that he's going
to step out of the competition so i
guess that means now you've won this
contest for sure isn't that wonderful?
i'm nicholas d wolfwood i'm
withdrawing from the final round
really but you were doing so
well for yourself may i ask why?
oh it's too much of a bother that's all
just give the prize to the other guy!
all right i can't do that!
what? look? huh?
well now that's how it is
Nicholas, you really are very good.
Would you consider eliminating Vash the
Stampede with your superb gunmanship?
If you do as I ask, I will guarantee
you the safety of that family.
And I'd even be willing to raise the
prize to 30 billion double dollars.
You mean 50-50?
I like a man with a head on his shoulders.
Gentlemen, the final round will now begin!
Ah! But why?
No, Vash!
Didn't you go over there to withdraw?
Here's the big money question.
Tell me, what do you see in the
window of that building over there?
And that just about sums it up.
Ready, go!
Run, Ash!
It's for the good of the family.
Just resign yourself and die.
Come on, get serious.
I'm saying that we all have
to make a few sacrifices.
Can I make a different one?
Now you've done it.
Well, this is what you got me
so plastered for yesterday.
Do you really think I'd
try something that cheap?
Yeah, I do!
After you went and signed
me up without asking...
You did the same to me!
Now the sixty billion double dollars is
all mine how fortunate now finish them off
Ahh!
What?
Why don't you kill them?
Help!
Throw me my luggage!
Huh?
But it's too big!
Come on, we can do it!
Step aside!
I'm gonna give it a push!
Hey, don't kill them!
Hey, whatever happens,
thou shalt not kill!
I won't let any more children suffer,
never again!
Wow, this is horrible.
I don't understand.
Why did you have to go and
injure so many of these people?
What kind of a churchman are you, anyway?
Hey, it's no big deal.
Nobody's dead, I kept my word.
Now then.
Mister, may the Lord
have mercy on your soul.
Or do you intend to pay me
the prize money after all?
All right, then. I'll pay it. I'll pay it.
Much obliged.
He sure has become awfully popular
all of a sudden, don't you think?
I knew he was no ordinary priest,
but I had no idea how unusual he was.
I can't hit you now!
There you are.
Thank you so much.
Ah, heck, think nothing of it.
What's wrong, Neil?
Dad!
Dear!
Guess my job is done.
Yep, sure looks like it.
For love and peace. Huh?
Get off!
No, Captain!
Anything but that! No!
No!
A choice between two things.
A forked road, a cross road, where men
given life must take in order to stay alive.
Whichever end they live
on, they lose something.
Whichever end they live on, they
are unable to find happiness.
But, are there really only
two paths to a forked road?
No, there are infinite paths we must take.
There is more than one path.
There is more than one path to the future.